<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Vida Glaser Real Estate Blog</title>
        <link>https://vidandco.github.io/vida-website/blog</link>
        <description>Vida Glaser Real Estate Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Earth Month]]></title>
            <link>https://vidandco.github.io/vida-website/blog/earth-month</link>
            <guid>https://vidandco.github.io/vida-website/blog/earth-month</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lower Your Home’s Carbon Footprint.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lower Your Home’s Carbon Footprint.</p>
<p>Are low carbon (footprint) homes becoming more common, is greener building becoming ‘the norm’?
Here is some information about building and retrofitting green energy into your home.
For some Cowichan Valley homeowners, a low carbon home is already a priority.
Do you envy your neighbours solar panels? For those who may have not yet taken
advantage of government incentives, don’t wait too long. There may be shifting
priorities in government spending. Take advantage of current rebates on EV
chargers, solar panels and upgrading your heating system to a heat
pump and upgrading insulation and windows. Rebates are all available from BC
Hydro through provincial funding, offering rebates up to $5,000 on eligible grid-
connected solar panels and up to an additional $5,000 for battery storage systems
to qualifying residential customers. The BC HYDRO website is very easy to use.
Last week I received a $600 rebate for an EV charger installed at my home!
“Rebates for (electricity) self-generation are one of the ways that we're
helping to meet the province's growing need for renewable electricity and
providing owners with more options for managing their energy use.”
Before you renovate, check out the incentives that will inch your home closer to a
lower carbon footprint and ultimately a passive home.
<a href="https://www.betterhomesbc.ca/rebates/energy-savings-program/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.betterhomesbc.ca/rebates/energy-savings-program/</a>
<a href="https://www.bchydro.com/powersmart/residential/rebates-programs/home-" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.bchydro.com/powersmart/residential/rebates-programs/home-</a>
renovation.html</p>
<p>Passive homes ( low carbon footprint homes) have been built mostly in Europe, but
are catching on in Canada.
"Passive homes aim to achieve the highest level of energy efficiency and climate-
consciousness possible by designing the home's function and style based on its
geographical location, solar orientation, and climatic region. High-efficiency
heating and cooling systems, as well as heat recovery ventilation (HRV) systems,
are incorporated, to further reduce the amount of energy needed to heat and cool
the home. Passive houses consume up to 90 percent less heating and cooling
energy than conventional buildings. Renewable energy systems such as solar
photovoltaic (solar panels) are often installed so that the building generates all of
its energy needs. With all of these features, passive houses produce little to no
greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions, making them sustainable and climate-friendly."</p>
<p>Canadian Federal government has recently implemented“The Canada Green Buildings Strategy: Transforming Canada’s buildings
sector for a net-zero and resilient future.
The Canadian Net-Zero Emissions Accountability Act enshrines in legislation the
Government of Canada’s commitment to reduce GHG emissions by 40-45% below
2005 levels by 2030 and to achieve net-zero emissions by 2050. Buildings
account for 18% of Canada’s emissions.”
The CGBS centers around three priorities:</p>
<ol>
<li>Accelerate retrofits</li>
<li>Build green and affordable from the start</li>
<li>Shape the buildings sector of the future.
Check <a href="https://natural-resources.canada.ca/energy-efficiency/home-energy-" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://natural-resources.canada.ca/energy-efficiency/home-energy-</a>
efficiency/canada-greener-homes-initiative
For the affordability program and more information.</li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="https://vidandco.github.io/vida-website/assets/images/docusaurus-plushie-banner-a60f7593abca1e3eef26a9afa244e4fb.jpeg" width="1500" height="500" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>earth</category>
            <category>month</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Home Ownership Aspirations]]></title>
            <link>https://vidandco.github.io/vida-website/blog/home-ownership</link>
            <guid>https://vidandco.github.io/vida-website/blog/home-ownership</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What does a morning cup of coffee and home ownership aspirations have in common?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What does a morning cup of coffee and home ownership aspirations have in common?</p>
<p>Thank you to my clients for the inspiration for this article.
Sometimes buying a home may involve looking at many properties to find what you
want, that is, if you are not certain what you would like your ideal home to be.
If you could picture yourself enjoying a cup of coffee in an idyllic setting where
would it be?</p>
<p>On a deck overlooking a forest? Or a sunny location with an ocean view? Would it
be at a gourmet kitchen counter? Or at a villa in Mexico? In a sunny high-rise with
your high tech coffee maker? Or in an enclosed patio full of fragrant flowers?
As a real estate agent who understands a client's needs as well as dreams,
answers to those questions are an imaginative way to understand your home
ownership aspirations.</p>
<p>Buying an ideal home means that your Realtor understands what you want. Just ‘a
house’ won’t do. If you like forested properties, it may mean you would like a rural
or semi-rural lifestyle. If you want a gourmet kitchen, a suitable kitchen space
would be the key aspect of your home search. Would you love to be in Mexico for
half the year? Then a 'lock it and leave it' condo would be ‘your thing’. New condos
or pre-sale condos provide the opportunity to own a maintenance free modern
home with all the new gadgets. Strata patio homes are great for single level living
with an outdoor space and low maintenance.</p>
<p>Where do you picture yourself?
Once you have decided where your idyllic setting is to enjoy your morning coffee,
the next step is to work toward your home ownership aspirations is to prepare
financially.</p>
<p>Contact a mortgage specialist and start planning. Financial planning and readiness
will help get you to your home ownership goals. If upsizing, start saving in a TFSA
and start paying off any outstanding debts. Speak to your mortgage broker before
you retire to take advantage of employment income. If you plan to down size,
think about investing into the next generation of homeowners (children) or invest
your money with retirement goals in mind.</p>
<p>I want to help you attain your real estate dreams. Contact me, Vida Glaser, a
Realtor with Pemberton Holmes, working and living in the Cowichan Valley. Let’s
have a coffee and talk about it!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>update</category>
            <category>local</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>